Guide to the Hopkins transportation collection, 1844-1969 (inclusive), 1936-1954 (bulk)
Department of Special Collections
Hopkins transportation collection,
1844-1969 (inclusive), 1936-1954 (bulk)
Special Collections M0200
4 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Hazel Elizabeth Sullivan, 1969.
Scope and Content
An explanation of a dispatcher's record of the movement of trains and a sample of dispatchers records from Beaumont, California, Los Angeles, California, and Mexicali, Baja California, covering the period 1936-1954. Also included are some xerox copies of reports dealing with railroads, and a newsreel clip about an aeroplane squadron committee.
Container List
- Dispatchers' Record of Movement of Trains and Description of Los Angeles Division of Southern Pacific Company, xerox copy, 5 p. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Dispatcher's Records, Beaumont, California 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Dispatcher's Records, Beaumont, California 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Dispatcher's Records, Beaumont, California 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Dispatcher's Records, Beaumont, California 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Dispatcher's Records, Los Angeles, California 1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Dispatcher's Records, Los Angeles, California 1938 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Dispatcher's Records, Los Angeles, California 1939 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Dispatcher's Records, Los Angeles, California 1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Dispatcher's Records, Los Angeles, California 1941 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Dispatcher's Records, Los Angeles, California 1942 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Dispatcher's Records, Los Angeles, California 1943 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Dispatcher's Records, Los Angeles, California 1944 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Dispatcher's Records, Los Angeles, California 1945 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Dispatcher's Records, Los Angeles, California 1946-1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Dispatcher's Records, Mexicali, Baja California 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Dispatcher's Records, Mexicali, Baja California 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Dispatcher's Records, Mexicali, Baja California 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Dispatcher's Records, Mexicali, Baja California 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Dispatcher's Records, Mexicali, Baja California 1945-1948 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Dispatcher's Records, Mexicali, Baja California 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Fishbein, M.H., Retention Plan for the Docketed Case Files- Interstate Commerce Commission, G.S.A., 9 p., xerox copy. (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Fishbein, M.H., Special Study of the Interstate Commerce Commission and Civil Aeronautics Board Tariffs, G.S.A., 8 p., xerox copy.
- Fishbein, M.H., Special Study of the Periodic Reports Submitted by Carriers to the Interstate Commerce Commission and the Civil Aeronautics Board, G.S.A., 7 p., xerox copy.
- Howerton, Joseph B., The Valuation Records of The Interstate Commerce Commission As A Source of Statistical Data Relating to American Railroads During the 19th Century,Preliminary Draft Prepared for the Conference on National Archives and Statistical Research, May 1968, 40 p., xerox copy. (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Myrick, David F., Refinancing and Rebuilding the Central Pacific: 1899-1910,Golden Spike Symposium, May 6-7, 1969, 42 p. and appendix, xerox copy. (Box 4, Folder 24)
- National Archives, Preliminary Inventories, No. 158, Records of the Commissioner of Railroads, Washington, 1964, 19 p., xerox copy. (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Los Angeles, The Aeronautical Society of Cal. creates its `Aeroplane Squadron Committee,' comprising Mayor Sebastien and many prominent citizens. Movie (clip from newsreel?) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  Moved to microfilm file cabinet, 29 Dec 80
- Pamphlets about Railroads (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - The Switch Post Feb. 1937
  - Train Talks 1936-1945
- Great Britain Railway Pamphlets, (1 Bound Volume) (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Railway Reports- British, (1 Bound Volume) (Box 5, Folder 29)
- TIME TABLE # 12 - LOS ANGELES + REDONDO RAILWAY EUREKA NEVADA RAILWAY - LOCAL PASSENGER TARIFF # 1 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- 1. Time table form 14, Southern Pacific, 4/40 San Francisco [UNK] Peninsula (Box 5, Folder 31)
- 2. New system of tunneling / by J. Brunel
- Plans & Sections of the Armagh Coleraine & Portrush Railway, (1 Bound Volume) (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 30)
- Highway and Transportation Maps of Idaho Counties 1937-1939, (1 Bound Volume) (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 31)
- Midland Railway Reports, (1 Bound Volume) (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 32)
- Midland Railway. Diagrams Illustrating the Application of Brakes to the Stopping of Trains., (1 Bound Volume) (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 33)
- Select Plans of Engineering Structures for Railroads and Highways., (1 Bound Volume) (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 34)
- Cours de Construction des Ponts., (1 Bound Volume) (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 35)
- Map - Orange Co.-santa Ana - Pacific Electric Railway Co. (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 36)
- 5 plans of U.S. tram bridges (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 37)
- 26 plans for French + German train bridges (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 38)
- York and North Midland Railway bound reports: (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 39.)
  - a. 1848 Feb 21Half Yearly general meeting
  - b. 1848 Aug 21Half Yearly general meeting
  - c. 1879 Sep 6Half Yearly general meeting
  - d. 1850 Feb 38Half Yearly general meeting
  - e. 1850 Aug 28Half Yearly general meeting
  - f. 1850 Aug 28Report to Directors
  - g. 1849 Oct 22Letter to shareholders
  - h. 1849 Oct 19Letter to shareholders
  - i. 1849 Oct 9Letter to shareholders
  - j. 1848 Nov 14Report to shareholders
- London and North Western Railway - bound reports (unlisted). (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 40.)
- London and North Western Railway, bound reports, with the reports of the London and Birmingham Railway Co. (unlisted). (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 41.)
- North Staffordshire Railway. Half yearly reports, 1846-1889.(bound in red leather). (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 42.)
- Midland Railway - Specification and general conditions of contract for the maintenance of way and works of the south branch of the Midland Railway (front board only). (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 43.)
- Agreement: Great Northern Railway Co. and Midland Railway Company, 1 June 1858.Various agreements bound together, pp 1-110. (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 44.)
- Midland Association Derby, Oct. 21, 1853,bound proceedings (printed). (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 45.)
- Midland Railways consolidation act, 10 May 1844.Handsewn, in hollinger folder. (Box 6 (oversize), Folder 46.)